Guide to the Herman Cohen Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Herman Cohen Papers,
1946-1979.
Cohen, Herman, 1905-
0.5 linear ft (61 items in 1 box).
Columbia University Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Butler Library, New York, New York 10027.
4078343
Biographical Note
Herman Cohen was the proprietor of the Chiswick Bookshop in New York City.
Scope and Content
Business correspondence, ducuments, and other materials from the calligrapher Margaret Adams, the printers R. Hunter Middleton, Henry Morris, and Herbert W. Simpson, and one letter from George Orwell.
Arrangement
Material is fully catalogued and arranged into one series: Series I: Herman Cohen Papers, 1946-1979.
Subjects
Adams, Margaret.; Morris, Henry, 1925-; Simpson, Herbert W.; Booksellers and bookselling
Acquisition
12/19/85 Papers Cohen, Herman Gift
Gift of Herman Cohen, 1985.
- Series I: Herman Cohen Papers, 1946-1979
  - Adams, Margaret
    - Correspondence
      - 1965 November 20 (Box 1)
      - 1966 March 1 (Box 1)
      - 1966 May 10 (Box 1)
      - 1966 July 20 (Box 1)
      - 1966 September 29 (Box 1)
      - 1966 November 9 (Box 1)
      - 1969 June 9 (Box 1)
      - 1969 June 20 (Box 1)
      - 1969 August 4 (Box 1)
      - 1969 August 21 (Box 1)
      - 1970 April 27 (Box 1)
      - 1970 May 30 (Box 1)
      - 1970 September 17 (Box 1)
      - 1970 September 30 (Box 1)
      - 1970 October 14 (Box 1)
      - 1977 June 21 (Box 1)
    - Invoice, 1970 September 15 (Box 1)
    - Packing List for Shipment to Herman Cohen, undated (Box 1)
  - Middleton, Robert Hunter--Correspondence, 1979 December 13 (Box 1)
  - Morris, Henry
    - Correspondence
      - 1965 April 21 (with carbon reply) (Box 1)
      - 1967 August 23 (with 2 related carbons) (Box 1)
      - 1967 October 10 (with galley proof of prospectus for Omnibus ) (Box 1)
  - Orwell, George--Correspondence, 1946 September 21 (with envelope and related items) (Box 1)
  - Simpson, Herbert W.
    - Correspondence
      - 1946-1947 (with related items) (Box 1)
      - 1968 June 5, July 26 (with carbon reply and related items) (Box 1)
  - Adams, Margaret--Miscellaneous Materials, undated (Box 1)
  - Clippings, Photostats, and Envelopes, 1957 undated (Box 1)